Welcome to the Securing Your Seller Account series.
It is important to protect yourself from
phishing attacks as fraudsters might attempt to steal your personal, financial, or other
sensitive information.
In this video, you'll learn what phishing is, how to protect yourself
from phishing, and how to recover from a phishing attack.
You might receive emails
from Amazon.
However, sometimes you may receive emails that are not really from Amazon, even
if at first glance they appear to be.
Instead, such emails are faked in an attempt to get
you to reveal sensitive account or banking information.
These fake emails, or what's
called spoofed or phishing emails, look similar to legitimate emails from Amazon.
Often these
emails direct you to a false website that looks similar to an Amazon website, where you
might be asked to give account information such as your email address and password combination.
Remember, Amazon never asks you to verify sensitive information via email.
Only enter
information when completing an order on our website, registering to sell on Amazon or
updating account information in Seller Central.
To protect yourself from responding to these
emails, you can follow some simple rules.
Number one, know what Amazon won't ask in
email.
Amazon will not ask you for your bank account information, credit card number, PIN,
your Seller Central account password, or credit card security code via email.
Instead, Amazon
will always ask you to update credit card details or account information via Seller Central.
Number two, review the email for grammatical or typographical errors.
Watch for poor grammar
or typographical errors.
Many phishing emails are translated from other languages or are
sent without being proofread.
Number three, check the return address.
Genuine emails from
Amazon.
com always come from an address ending in @amazon.
com.
Check the email's header
information.
If the received from reply to or return path for the email does not come
from @amazon.
com, it is not from Amazon.
The method you use to check the header information
varies depending upon the email program you use.
The following are some examples of fraudulent
return addresses.
Seller-performance@payments-amazon.
com, Amazon-security@hotmail.
com, or Amazon-payments
@
msn.
com.
Number four, review the email for mismatched hyperlinks. ,
some phishing
emails include a hyperlink or a button that looks as though it will take you to your Amazon
account.
However, if you hover your mouse over the link, you often can see the underlying
false website address either as a pop-up or as information in the browser status bar.
When in doubt, do not click on the links in the email.
Instead, open a new window and
go directly to Amazon.
com or the Seller Central website.
Number five, check the website address.
Some phishers set up spoofed websites that look
similar to the Amazon website and use the word Amazon somewhere in the URL.
We will never
use a combination such as security-amazon.
com or amazon.
com.
biz in the URL.
Genuine Amazon
website URLs always end with .
amazon.
com or sellercentral.
com.
Always check that
the URL starts with HTTPS and is preceded by a secure lock icon.
If you've entered your password on what you think might be a malicious website, then change
your password on amazon.
com immediately.
To do that, go to the amazon.
com sign-in page
and click on "Forgot your password." If you've entered your credit card information
on what you think might be a malicious website or replied to an email with that information,
immediately contact your credit card company.
Note, if you receive a new replacement card,
then don't forget to update your new card on amazon.
com.
Amazon takes phishing attempts
very seriously.
To report a suspicious email or learn more about phishing, go to amazon.
com/security.